<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: apps | Abe Massry]]></title>
  <link href="http://abemassry.com/blog/categories/apps/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://abemassry.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-04T11:58:18-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://abemassry.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Abe Massry]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Near Field Messenger - Connect with People Around You]]></title>
    <link href="http://abemassry.com/blog/2014/04/15/near-field-messenger/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-15T10:48:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://abemassry.com/blog/2014/04/15/near-field-messenger</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Near Field Messenger (NFM) - Connect with People Around You.  I have had this idea for a while and I wanted to get it out there to see what people thought.  Leave me your feedback and feel free to ask me questions if this is something you're interested in learning more about.</p>

<h2>The Problem</h2>

<p>After I graduated college I found myself far away from friends. Facebook wasn't really a help because it was a directory of all my friends that live too far away to hang out on a regular basis. Twitter is pretty good at finding new people that you get along with, but half of my twitter friends are on the other side of the country.  What if there was a way to connect with people that lived close by?</p>

<h2>The Solution</h2>

<p>Near Field Messenger.  What if you could instantly talk to the closest 50 people around you in a shared chat room, right from your smartphone?</p>

<p>In New York City this would be your city block</p>

<p><img src="https://wsend.net/b9deed6d28c44046fa9a5f904721aac9/nyc.jpg" title="NYC" ></p>

<p>but in Wyoming it would be the entire state</p>

<p><img src="https://wsend.net/85f62e0e62730deb9ca9284ae08790f9/wyoming.jpg" title="Wyoming" >.</p>

<h2>How</h2>

<p>How would something like this work? What if there is one person outside the 50 people and there is no one else around them?  The idea I had was to start out with a small area and use fuzzy logic, so that if there is 50 - 60 people that's ok.  Why limit it? Because you want to keep it local.</p>

<h3>Really, How?</h3>

<p>OK so it all works like bubbles.  The bubbles are an area and when two peoples bubbles coalesce that becomes a larger bubble so you wont have people that are left out.</p>

<p><img src="https://wsend.net/fcb24b1a984afad0668577e22e75020e/bubbles.jpg" title="Bubbles" ></p>

<p>After there are over 50 people new bubbles can be formed and the visualization could be different colors.</p>

<p>The point is to get people that are physically close, chatting with each other just so they have someone to talk to and possibly hang out with.</p>

<p>After they meet people they would like to hang out with there can be private messages and you should be able to import your contacts and make new contacts.</p>

<h2>Why</h2>

<p>After people graduate highschool and move away or graduate college they lose touch with some friends.  They still keep those friends but they are far away and don't get to see each other in person that much. And it gets really lonely.  The same thing happened to me and I've been really lonely and searching for friends, but outside of a school environment it's hard to approach people and it's hard to find people that are free and want to hang out, where you don't have to drive really far to get there.  I don't live in a city and I feel like there are a lot of other people out there who are lonely too and just want someone to talk to.</p>

<h2>Other apps out there / Competitors</h2>

<p><a href="http://meetup.com">meetup.com</a> is there and you can find people in your local area who are interested in the same things you are.  The meeting times are formal and there is a lot more to do in cities than in the suburbs or rural areas.</p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/popcorn-messaging/id718416705?mt=8">Popcorn Messaging</a> is an app that is similar but only has a 1 mile radius and is kind of like a bulletin board where people can leave messages if no one else is actively using the app in your area.  If Popcorn was to change their app a little it might be similar to NFM.</p>

<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/ralph-chat/id782873767?mt=8">Ralph Chat</a> is an app that is similar but it has a radius as well, it does have global chats so there are people to talk to but they might not be in your area.  If they changed their app or added a semi-local chat room it might be similar to NFM.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>I hope you like this app idea and support me in making it happen.</p>

<p>Vote on it at: <a href="http://competition.coshx.com/ideas/near-field-messenger">The Coshx 50k Competition</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[5 Things I use for Productivity]]></title>
    <link href="http://abemassry.com/blog/2013/10/15/5-things-i-use-for-productivity/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-15T13:29:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://abemassry.com/blog/2013/10/15/5-things-i-use-for-productivity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Before I consciously thought about productivity I had an organically grown method and wide range of tools I used that wasn’t necessarily the most productive way of being productive.  Then I stepped back and looked at what worked the best and what didn’t.</p>

<h2>First the history:</h2>

<p>In highschool and college we had planners issued to us once a year.  Everything I did went into them, and I stayed productive and was on top of things because I checked the planner relentlessly, I always carried it with me because I carried a backpack everywhere I went.</p>

<p>When I started working I bought a pocket sized planner but it was too small and it could fit easily in a jacket pocket but not carry it with me.</p>

<p>Then came the smart phones, first it was email and calendaring, this was good but not the best. It was difficult to check and the phone didn’t have everything plainly listed, you had to search for what you had to do that day.  One positive was, now there were automated reminders and alarms that went off when a meeting was coming up.</p>

<p>These tools were difficult to use but you could use them properly to get by.</p>

<h2>What I use now:</h2>

<p>I’ll list these in reverse order from now as I have just started using the newer tools and they are more at the forefront of my mind because they haven’t made it into my unthinking routine.</p>

<ol>
<li><p><a href="http://www.bulletjournal.com/">Bullet Journal</a></p>

<p> I saw this just recently and I realized I was the most productive when I had one true source, in a handwritten book, that I referred to.  I jumped in headfirst and said “This is what I’ll be using from now on”.  It make sense to me and the other parts of the planner that were printed on the page, I draw them in.  The only problem in my usage of this is I’m not always able to carry something with me, as it needs to fit in my pocket which is why I also use:</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://evernote.com/">Evernote</a></p>

<p> I use it as a backup to bullet journal when I want to take a note to write it down later and I only have my phone with me, or I use it to take a picture of something that I want to remember.  It kinda serves the role of my own personal external memory. I used to use a point and shoot digital camera for this.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://lift.do/">Lift</a></p>

<p> I usually check this around 2 times a day.  As soon as I get up, and before I go to bed.  This reminds me of the things I have to do on a daily basis, but since I should be doing them every day, I wouldn’t write them down. I also use this to visually show progress on a long running goal.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://tempo.ai/">Tempo</a></p>

<p> I switched to tempo for my calendaring app and I really like the experience.  I can enter something on google calendar (which I use for desktop calendaring) and it will automatically show up and pull in relevant data to each meeting or appointment.</p></li>
<li><p>My Brain</p>

<p> All the others are some form of Tech (analog tech in the case of the bullet journal).  But in an ideal world I’d have a photographic memory, I would remember all the important things as well as the semi important things, and an internal chronometer that would alert me when the things in my calendar were coming up.</p>

<p> The reason why I use items 1-4 and why I think they are useful is that it frees my mind to focus on one task at a time and I can complete the task efficiently when I’m able to focus.  I actually forget an item temporarily when I write it down or put it in a calendar and either a machine reminds me I have something to do or I have a break in work and I wonder what it is I have to do and it’s written down.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>I’m Abe and I make a tool for being more productive on the command line and on the web for sending files.  Check out <a href="https://wsend.net">Wsend</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
