<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: mashrd | Abe Massry]]></title>
  <link href="http://abemassry.com/blog/categories/mashrd/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://abemassry.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-18T13:35:15-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://abemassry.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Abe Massry]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observations on mashrd]]></title>
    <link href="http://abemassry.com/blog/2012/10/23/observations-on-mashrd/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-23T15:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://abemassry.com/blog/2012/10/23/observations-on-mashrd</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just a quick observation, it seems like more stories that make it to the popular section are about either politics or Apple products.  I might make a chart and have graphs to back up my observations next time.  But it makes sense given the time of year it is and the election is happening in a week and Apple just unveiled more products.  Still there is a lot of news that doesn't see the light of day.  Not sure if it's a good thing or a bad thing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[mashrd update]]></title>
    <link href="http://abemassry.com/blog/2012/10/23/mashrd-update/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-23T15:23:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://abemassry.com/blog/2012/10/23/mashrd-update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just wanted to tell you about some of the design choices for mashrd. I wanted to support the big social networks to start out with. I really wanted to have App.net but I could not find a button for them. Buffer, bufferapp.com has a button but I had trouble integrating it and I will delve deeper into the API soon. The other issue is for the popular page the network with the highest count gets the button. So that is usually Facebook or Twitter. When App.net has a button I can make a companion site with App.net as it's own news listing site, if there is demand for it.  I co-posted this post on the mashrd about page as well as here. <a href="http://mashrd.com/about">About mashrd</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
